I believe in America.
America has made my fortune...
and I raised my daughter in the American fashion.
I give her freedom, but I taught her...
never to dishonor her family.
She found a boyfriend. Not an Italian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out late. I didn't protest.
Two months ago, he took her for a drive...
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey...
and then they tried to take advantage of her.
She resisted.
She kept her honor.
So they beat her like an animal.
When I went to the hospital, her nose was broken...
her jaw was shattered...
held together by wire.
She couldn't even weep because of the pain.
But I wept. Why did I weep?
She was the light of my life.
Beautiful girl.
Now she will never be beautiful again.
Sorry.
I went to the police like a good American.
These two boys were brought to trial.
A judge sentence them to three years in prison...
and suspend their sentence.
Suspended sentence.
They went free that very day.
I stood in the courtroom like a fool.
And those two bastard, they smiled at me.
Then I said to my wife, For justice...
we must go to don Corleone.
Why did you go to the police?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me?
Tell me anything, but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
We've known each other many
years, but this is the first time...
you ever came to me for counsel or for help.
I can't remember the last time that you invited me...
to your house for a cup of coffee...
even though my wife is godmother to your only child.
But let's be frank.
You never wanted my friendship...
and you were afraid to be in my debt.
I didn't want to get into trouble.
I understand.
You found paradise in America.
You had a good trade, made a good living.
Police protected you, and there were courts of law.
So you didn't need a friend like me.
But now you come to me and you say...
don Corleone, give me justice.
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship.
You don't even think to call me Godfather.
Instead, you come into my house...
on the day my daughter is to be married...
and you ask me to do murder for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice. Your daughter is still alive.
They must suffer then as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonier.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfully?
If you'd come to me in friendship...
then the scum that ruined your daughter...
would be suffering this very day.
And if, by chance...
an honest man like yourself should make enemies...
then they would become my enemies.
And then they would fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather.
Good.
Someday, and that day may never come...
I'll call upon you to do a service for me.
But until that day...
accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
Grazie, Godfather.
Give this to Clemenza.
I want reliable people...
people that aren't going to be carried away.
I mean, we're not murderers...
in spite of what this undertaker says.
- Where's Michael? - What? Don't worry.
It's early. He'll be here.
We're not taking it.
We're not taking the picture without Michael.
- What's the matter, Sonny? - It's Michael.
Don Barzini.
Hey, Paulie!
Let me have some wine.
Paulie! More wine.
Scusi, please.
You look terrific on the floor.
What are you, a dance judge or something?
Go take a walk around
the neighborhood. Do your job.
Sandra, come on. Do me a favor. Watch the kids.
- Don't let 'em run wild.
- You watch yourself, all right?
Twenty or thirty grand.
In small bills, cash.
In that little silk purse.
If this was somebody else's wedding.
Hey, Paulie! I got two gobbagool...
gabagol and a prosciutto.
Stupid jerk!
Hey, what's the matter?
Have to go back to work.
It's part of the wedding.
No Sicilian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don Corleone, I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me to your home...
Get outta here.
This is a private party. Go on.
What is it? Hey, my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI don't respect nothin'.
Hey, come here, come here. Come here!
There.
But towards the end he was paroled...
to help with the American war effort.
For the last six months, he's been
working at my pastry shop.
Nazorine, my friend, what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over...
this boy, Enzo, they want
to repatriate him back to Italy.
Godfather, I have a daughter.
See, she and Enzo...
You want Enzo to stay in this country...
and you want your daughter to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr. Hagen. Thank you.
And wait till you see the beautiful wedding cake...
I made for your daughter.
Like this, with the bride
and the groom and...
- Who should I give this job to?
- Not to our paisan.
Give it to a Jew congressman in another district.
Who else is on the list?
Hey, Michael. How are you?
Hello.
He's not on the list,
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this necessary?
He didn't expect to be invited to the wedding...
so he wanted to thank you.
All right.
Don Corleone, I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me to your home...
on the wedding day of your daughter.
And may their first child be a masculine child.
- Don...
- Michael?
Don Corleone...
That man over there is talking to himself.
See that scary guy over there?
He's a very scary guy.
Who is he? What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi...
and he helps my father out sometimes.
Wait a minute. He's coming over here.
You look terrific!
My brother Tom Hagen. This is Kay Adams.
How do you do? Nice to meet you.
Your father's been asking for you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
I'll be there.
If he's your brother,
why does he have a different name?
When my brother Sonny was a kid...
he found Tom Hagen in the street,
and he had no home.
So my father took him in...
and he's been with us ever since.
He's a good lawyer.
Not a Sicilian, but...
I think he's gonna be consigliere.
- What's that? - That's...
like a counselor, an advisor.
Very important to the family.
You like your lasagna?
Don Corleone, I am honored and grateful...
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding...
on the day of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope that their first child...
be a masculine child.
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
For your daughter's bridal purse.
Thank you, Luca, my most valued friend.
Don Corleone, I'm gonna leave you now...
because I know you are busy.
Thank you.
Senator Cauly apologized
for not coming personally...
but said you'd understand.
Also some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
Johnny!
I love you.
Hey, Johnny, look over here!
He came all the way from California
to come to the wedding.
- I told you he was going to come.
- It's been two years.
- He's probably in trouble again.
- He's a good godson.
Sing a song.
Michael, you never told me
you knew Johnny Fontane.
- Sure. You wanna meet him?
- Huh? Oh, well, sure.
My father helped him with his career.
- For my Connie.
- He did? How?
I have but one
- Let's listen to the song.
- No.
Heart
This heart I bring you
I have but one heart
To share with you
I have but one dream
That I can cling to
You are the one dream
I'll pray comes true
Please, Michael. Tell me.
My darling, until I saw you
When Johnny was first starting out...
he was signed to this personal service contract...
with a big bandleader.
And as his career got better and better...
he wanted to get out of it.
Now, Johnny is my father's godson...
and my father went to see this bandleader...
and he offered him $10,000 to let Johnny go.
But the bandleader said no.
So the next day my father went to see him...
only this time with Luca Brasi.
And within an hour, he signed a release...
for a certified check of $1,000.
How'd he do that?
My father made him an offer he couldn't refuse.
What was that?
Luca Brasi held a gun to his head...
and my father assured him
that either his brains...
or his signature would be on the contract.
That's a true story.
That's my family, Kay. It's not me.
Beautiful!
My godson comes all the way from California.
Give him a glass of wine.
I'll take care of it.
I want you to find Santino.
Tell him to come to the office.
How are you, Fredo?
My brother Fredo. This is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How ya doin'?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah. This is your friend, huh?
I don't know what to do. My voice is weak.
It's weak.
Anyway, if I had this part in the picture...
it puts me right back up on top again.
But this...
this man out there, he won't give it to me.
- The head of the studio.
- What's his name?
Woltz. He won't give it to me...
and he says there's no chance, no chance.
Sonny?
Sonny, you in there?
- What?
- The old man wants to see you.
Yeah, one minute.
A month ago, he bought
the movie rights to this book.
A best-seller.
And the main character
is a guy just like me.
Why, I wouldn't even
have to act.
Just be myself.
Oh, Godfather,
I don't know what to do.
You can act like a man!
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out?
A Hollywood finocchio that cries like a woman?
What can I do?
What is that nonsense?
Ridiculous!
- You spend time with your family?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because the man who doesn't
spend time with his family...
can never be a real man.
Come here.
You look terrible. I want you to eat.
I want you to rest well, and a month from now...
this Hollywood big shot's
gonna give you what you want.
Too late. They start shooting in a week.
I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.
Now just go outside, enjoy yourself...
and forget about all this nonsense.
Listen. I want you to leave it all to me.
All right.
What time does my daughter
leave with the bridegroom?
In a few minutes, right after they cut the cake.
Now, your new son-in-law,
we give him something important.
Never. Give him a living...
but never discuss the family business with him.
What else?
Virgil Sollozzo called.
We have to give him a day sometime next week.
We'll discuss him when you
come back from California.
When am I going to California?
I want you to go tonight.
I want you to talk to this movie big shot...
and settle this business for Johnny.
If there's nothing else, I'd like
to go to my daughter's wedding.
Carlo, we're gonna take the picture.
Wait a minute.
No, Michael, not me.
Just a little closer.
Okay, that's it. Just like that now. Hold it.
Isn't that nice?
All right, start talking.
I was sent by a friend of Johnny Fontane.
This friend is my client and would
give his undying friendship...
to Mr. Woltz if Mr. Woltz
would grant us a small favor.
Woltz is listening.
Give Johnny the part in that new
war film you're starting next week.
And what favor would your friend...
grant Mr. Woltz?
You're gonna have some union problems.
My client could make them disappear.
Also, one of your top stars has just moved...
from marijuana to heroin.
- Are you trying to muscle me?
- Absolutely not.
Listen to me,
you smooth-talking son of a bitch!
Let me lay it on the line for you
and your boss, whoever he is!
Johnny Fontane will never get that movie.
I don't care how many dago, guinea, wop...
grease ball goombahs come outta the woodwork.
I'm German-lrish.
Well, let me tell you something,
my kraut mick friend.
I'll make so much trouble for you,
you won't know what hit you.
I'm a lawyer. I have not threatened...
I know almost every big lawyer
in New York. Who are you?
I have a special practice. I handle one client.
Now, you have my number. I'll wait for your call.
By the way, I admire your pictures very much.
Check him out.
- This is really beautiful.
- Look at this.
Used to decorate the palace of a king.
Oh, yeah. Very nice.
Why didn't you say you worked for Corleone, Tom?
I thought you were just
some cheap, two-bit hustler...
Johnny was running in,
trying to bluff me.
I don't like to use his name
unless it's really necessary.
- How's your drink, Tom?
- Fine.
Come with me. I want to show you
something really beautiful.
You do appreciate beauty, don't you, Tom?
There you are. $600,000 on four hooves.
I'll bet Russian czars...
never paid that kind of dough for a single horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not gonna race him, though.
I'm gonna put him out to stud.
Beautiful.
- Thanks, Tony.
- You're welcome.
- Come on.
- Let's get something to eat.
Mr. Corleone is Johnny's godfather.
To the Italian people, that's a very religious...
sacred, close relationship.
I respect that.
Just tell him he should ask me anything else.
This is one favor I can't give him.
He never asks a second favor
when he's been refused the first.
- Understood?
- You don't understand.
Johnny Fontane never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him. It'll make him a big star.
I'm gonna run him out of the business.
Let me tell you why.
Johnny Fontane ruined
one of Woltz International's...
most valuable proteges.
For five years, we had her under training.
Singing lessons, acting lessons, dancing lessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands of dollars on her.
I was gonna make her a big star.
And let me be even more frank.
Just to show you that I'm not a hard-hearted man...
that it's not all dollars and cents.
She was beautiful.
She was young, she was innocent!
She was the greatest piece of ass I've ever had...
and I've had 'em all over the world!
And then Johnny Fontane comes along...
with his olive oil voice
and guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me look ridiculous...
and a man in my position can't afford...
to be made to look ridiculous!
Now you get the hell outta here!
And if that goombah tries any rough stuff...
you tell him I ain't no bandleader.
Yeah. I heard that story.
Thank you for the dinner
and a very pleasant evening.
If your car could take me
to the airport...
Mr. Corleone is a man who insists
on hearing bad news immediately.
- You're not too tired, Tom?
- No, I slept on the plane.
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
Now...
Sollozzo is known as The Turk.
He's supposed to be
very good with a knife...
but only in matters of business...
with some sort of reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey where they grow the poppy...
and in Sicily he has the plants
to process them into heroin.
Now, he needs cash and he needs
protection from the police...
for which he gives apiece of the action.
I couldn't find out how much.
The Tattaglia family is behind him here in New York.
Now, they have to be in it for something.
Santino Corleone.
What about his prison record?
Two terms, one in Italy, one here.
He's known as a top narcotics man.
Santino, what do you think?
There's a lot of money in that white powder.
Tom?
I say, yes, there's more
money potential in narcotics...
than anything else we're looking at.
If we don't get into it, somebody else will.
Maybe one of the five families, maybe all of them.
With the money they earn...
they can buy more police and political power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have the unions, we have the gambling...
and they're the best things
to have, but narcotics...
is a thing of the future.
If we don't get a piece of that action...
we risk everything we have.
Not now, but ten years from now.
So? What's your answer gonna be, Pop?
I need a man who has powerful friends.
I need a million dollars in cash.
I need, don Corleone, those politicians...
that you carry in your pocket
like so many nickels and dimes.
What is the interest for my family?
Thirty percent.
In the first year, your end
should be 3, 4 million dollars.
And then it would go up.
And what is the interest
for the Tattaglia family?
My compliments.
I'll take care of the Tattaglias outta my share.
So, I receive 30% for finance...
political influence and legal protection.
- That's what you're telling me.
- That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider
a million dollars in cash...
just finance...
I said that I would see you because...
I heard that you were a serious man...
to be treated with respect.
But I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true, I have a lot of friends in politics.
But they wouldn't be friendly very long...
if they knew my business was drugs
instead of gambling...
which they regard as a harmless vice.
- But drugs is a dirty business.
- No, don Corleone...
It doesn't make any difference to me...
what a man does for a living, you understand...
but your business is...
a little dangerous.
If you're worried about security for your million...
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
You're tellin' me the Tattaglias
guarantee our investment...
Wait a minute.
I have a sentimental weakness for my children...
and I spoil them, as you can see.
They talk when they should listen.
But anyway...
Signor Sollozzo, my no is final...
and I wish to congratulate you
on your new business.
I know you'll do very well,
and good luck to you...
especially since your interests
don't conflict with mine.
Thank you.
Come here.
What's the matter with you?
I think your brain is going soft...
from all that comedy you're
playing with that young girl.
Never tell anybody outside the
family what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom, what... What is this nonsense?
It's from Johnny. He's starring in that new film.
Well, take it away.
Take it over there.
And...
tell Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a little worried
about this Sollozzo fellow.
I want you to find out what
he's got under his fingernails.
Go to the Tattaglias...
and make them think...
that you're not too happy with our family...
and find out what you can.
And I got something
for your mother and for Sonny...
and a tie for Freddy...
and Tom Hagen got the Reynolds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- Me?
Oh, just you.
Tell Paulie to get the car. We're going.
Okay, Pa.
I'll have to get it myself.
Paulie called in sick this morning.
Paulie's a good kid.
I don't mind gettin' the car.
Luca, I am Bruno Tattaglia.
I know.
Scotch? Prewar.
You know who I am?
- Merry Christmas.
- Yeah.
I'm glad I run into you. I wanna talk to you.
I haven't got time.
Oh, make time, consigliere. Get in the car.
What are you worried about?
Get in.
- I'm gonna buy some fruit.
- Okay, Pa.
Hi. Merry Christmas.
I want some fruit over there.
Gimme three of them.
No, that one.
Fredo!
Papa.
Papa!
Would you like me better if I were a nun...
like in the story, you know?
Then would you like me better
if I were Ingrid Bergman?
Now that's a thought.
No, I would not like you better
if you were Ingrid Bergman.
- Mike...
- What's the matter?
They don't say if he's dead or alive.
- Sonny, Michael.
- Michael, where you been?
Is he all right?
We don't know yet. There's all kinds of stories.
He wash it bad, Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
Where you been? I was worried.
Didn't Tom tell you? I called.
No. Look, come home, kid.
You should be with Mama, you hear?
All right.
Oh, my God.
Go. Who is it?
Open up. It's Clemenza.
What?
There's more news about your old man.
The word is out on the street he's already dead.
Shut your mouth. What's the matter with you?
Jesus Christ! Take it easy.
- Where was Paulie?
- Paulie was out sick.
- He's been sick all winter.
- How many times he been sick?
Only maybe three, four times.
I asked Freddy if he wants
a different bodyguard.
- He said no.
- Pick him up now.
I don't care how sick he is.
If he's breathing', I want you to
bring him to my father's house now.
- You want me to send people here?
- No, just you and him. Go ahead.
All right.
I'm havin' a couple of our people come to the house.
- Hello?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
In about three hours, he'll be
released with our proposition.
Listen to everything he has
to say before you do anything.
What's done is done.
And don't lose that famous temper
of yours, huh, Sonny?
No, I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in
the muscle end of the family...
so I don't want you to be scared.
I want you to help the Corleones...
and I want you to help me.
We got him outside his office...
about an hour after we picked you up.
Drink it.
So now it's up to you to make
the peace between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot for my deal, wasn't he?
And you knew it was the right thing to do.
Sonny will come after you
with everything he's got.
That'll be his first reaction, sure.
That's why you gotta talk some sense into him.
The Tattaglia family is behind me
with all their people.
The other New York families
will go along with anything...
that will prevent a full-scale war.
Let's face it, in all due respect...
the don, rest in peace, was slippin'.
Ten years ago, could I have gotten to him?
Well, now he's dead.
He's dead, and nothing can bring him back.
So you gotta talk to Sonny.
You gotta talk to the caporegimes...
that Tessio, that fat Clemenza.
It's good business, Tom.
I'll try.
But even Sonny won't be able
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah. Well...
Let me worry about Luca.
You just talk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
I'll do my best.
Good.
Now, you can go.
I don't like violence, Tom.
I'm a businessman.
Blood is a big expense.
He's still alive.
They hit him with five shots, and he's still alive!
Well, that's bad luck for me...
and bad luck for you
if you don't make that deal.
Your mother's over
in the hospital with your father.
Looks like he's gonna
pull through, thank God.
- That's a lot of bad blood.
- What do you think?
It's too far. I think it's too personal.
- The don will consider this over.
- You gonna kill all those guys?
- Stay out of it, Mickey.
- Sollozzo's the key.
You get rid of him, everything falls into line.
What about Luca? Sollozzo
didn't seem worried about Luca.
I don't know. If Luca sold out,
we're in a lot of trouble.
Has anyone been able to get in touch with Luca?
We've been tryin' all night.
He might be shacked up.
Mick, try him again.
Luca never sleeps over with a broad.
He always goes home when he's through.
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
What do we do if the old man dies, God forbid?
If we lose the old man...
we lose our political contacts
and half our strength.
The other New York families might
wind up supporting Sollozzo...
just to avoid a long destructive war.
This is almost 1946.
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
you'll make the deal, Sonny.
That's easy for you to say. He's not your father.
I was as much a son to him as you or Mike.
What is it?
Hey, Paulie, I thought I told you to stay put.
The guy at the gates, they say they got a package.
Yeah? Tessio, go see what it is.
- You want me to hang around?
- Yeah, hang around.
- You all right?
- I'm fine.
Yeah? There's some food
in the icebox. You hungry?
- No, it's all right. Thanks.
- How 'bout a little brandy?
- That's good to sweat it out.
- Sure.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
I want you to take care
of that son of a bitch right away.
Paulie sold out the old man.
I don't wanna see him again.
Make that first thing on your list.
Understood.
Hey, Mickey, tomorrow
you get a couple of guys.
Go to Luca's apartment.
Wait for him to show up.
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directly.
Yeah.
Listen, hang around the house
on the phone. It'll be a big help.
Try Luca again. Go ahead.
- What the hell is this?
- It's a Sicilian message.
It means Luca Brasi sleeps with the fishes.
- I'm goin' now.
- What time you gonna be home?
I don't know. Probably late.
- Don't forget the cannoli.
- Yeah, yeah.
Rocco, sit on the other side.
You block the rearview mirror.
Sonny's runnin' wild.
He's thinkin' of goin' to the mattresses already.
We gotta find a spot over on the West Side.
We'll try 309 West 43rd Street.
You know any good spots
on the West Side?
- Yeah, I'll think about it.
- Think while you're drivin'.
I wanna hit New York sometime this month.
And watch out for the kids when you're backin' out.
Paulie, I want you to go
down 39th Street. Colosanto's.
Pick up 18 mattresses for the guys
to sleep. Bring me the bill.
- Yeah, all right.
- Make sure they're clean.
Those guys are gonna be stuck up
in there for a long time.
They're clean. They told me
they exterminate them.
Exterminate? That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate. Get this guy.
See how we don't exterminate you.
- Youse funny, or what?
- Hey, Paulie?
- Yeah, Rocco, what'd you do?
- No, me. It wasn't me.
- It's gotta be him.
- Pull over.
I gotta take a leak.
Leave the gun.
Take the cannoli.
- Yeah?
- You're wanted on the telephone.
- Who is it?
- It's some girl.
Hello, Kay?
How's your father?
He's good. He's gonna make it.
I love you.
I love you!
- Michael?
- Yeah, I know.
Tell me you love me.
- I can't talk.
- Can't you say it?
Yeah, I'll see you tonight.
Why don't you tell that nice girl you love her?
I love you with all o' my heart!
If I don't see you again a-soon, I'm-a gonna die!
Come over here, kid. Learn somethin'.
You might have to cook for 20 guys someday.
You see? You start out with a little bit of oil.
Then you fry some garlic.
Then you throw in some
tomatoes, some tomato paste.
You fry it. You make sure it doesn't stick.
When you got it to a boil, shove in
all your sausage and meatballs.
And a little bit of wine.
And a little bit of sugar.
- And that's my trick.
- Why don't you cut the crap?
I got more important things for you to do.
- How's Paulie?
- Won't see him no more.
- Where you going?
- To the city.
Send some bodyguards with him.
- I'm just going to see Pop.
- Send somebody with him.
He'll be all right. Sollozzo knows he's a civilian.
- All right. Be careful, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
I have to go.
Can I go with you?
No, Kay. There's gonna be detectives there.
People from the press.
I'll ride in a cab.
I don't want you to get involved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire...
and I'll call you at your parents' house.
When will I see you again, Michael?
I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here now.
I'm Michael Corleone. This is my father.
There's nobody here.
What happened to the guards?
Your father just had too many visitors.
They interfered with hospital service.
The police made them leave about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 4-5-6-2-0, please.
Nurse, wait a minute. Stay here.
Sonny, Michael. I'm at the hospital.
Listen. I got here late. There's nobody here.
Nobody. No Tessio's men,
no detectives, nobody.
- Pop is all alone.
- Don't panic. We'll send somebody.
I won't panic.
I'm sorry, but you will have to leave.
You and I are gonna move
my father to another room.
Can you disconnect those tubes
so we can move the bed out?
- That's out of the question.
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here to kill him.
You understand?
Now, help me, please.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo... the baker.
- You remember me?
- Enzo?
- Yes, Enzo.
- You better get out of here, Enzo.
There's gonna be trouble.
If there is trouble, I stay here to help you...
For your father.
All right, listen.
Wait for me outside, in front of the hospital.
All right? I'll be out in a minute. Go ahead.
Just lie here, Pop. I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these. Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket like you have a gun.
You'll be all right.
You'll be okay.
You did good.
Here he is.
All right, hold still.
I thought I got all you guinea hoods locked up.
What are you doing here?
What happened to the men who
were guarding my father, Captain?
Why, you little punk.
What the hell are you doing,
telling me my business?
I pulled them guys off of here.
You get out of here
and stay away from this hospital.
I'm not moving until you put some
guards around my father's room.
Phil, take him in.
The kid's clean, Captain. He's a war hero.
- He's never been busted...
- Goddamn it, I said take him in.
What's the Turk paying you
to set up my father, Captain?
Take a hold of him. Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the attorney for the Corleone family.
These men are private detectives
hired to protect Vito Corleone.
They're licensed to carry firearms.
If you interfere, you'll have to
appear before a judge...
in the morning and show cause.
All right, let him go.
Come on.
What's with all the new faces?
Gonna need 'em now.
After the hospital thing, Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno Tattaglia at 4:00 this morning.
Jesus Christ.
Looks like a fortress around here.
A hundred button men on the street, 24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair
on his ass, he's dead. Believe me.
Hey, Michael, come here.
Let me look at you.
You look beautiful. Just beautiful.
You're gorgeous.
Hey, listen to this. The Turk, he wants to talk.
Imagine the nerve on this son of a bitch.
Craps out last night,
he wants a meeting today.
- What'd he say?
- What did he say?
He wants us to send Michael
to hear the proposition.
And the promise is that the deal
is so good that we can't refuse.
What about Bruno Tattaglia?
That's part of the deal.
Bruno cancels out what they did to my father.
Sonny, we ought to hear
what they have to say.
No more. Not this time, Consigliere.
No more meetings, no discussions,
no more Sollozzo tricks.
You give them one message...
I want Sollozzo.
If not, it's all-out war.
We go to the mattresses.
Some of the other families
won't sit still for a war.
- Then they hand me Sollozzo.
- Your father wouldn't like this.
- This is business, not personal.
- They shot my father.
Even shooting your father
was business, not personal, Sonny.
Well, then business will have to suffer.
And do me a favor, Tom...
No more advice on how to patch things up.
Just help me win, please. All right?
I found out about this McCluskey
who broke Mike'sjaw.
What about him?
He's definitely on Sollozzo's
payroll, and for big money.
McCluskey has agreed
to be the Turk's bodyguard.
What you have to understand, Sonny...
is that while Sollozzo's being guarded like this...
he is invulnerable.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York police captain. Never.
It would be disastrous. All the
five families would come after you.
The Corleone family would be outcast.
Even the old man's political
protection would run for cover.
So do me a favor.
Take this into consideration.
All right, we'll wait.
We can't wait.
Can't wait.
I don't care what Sollozzo says about a deal.
He's gonna kill Pop. That's it.
That's the key for him.
Got to get Sollozzo.
Mike is right.
Let me ask you something first.
What about this McCluskey?
What do we do with this cop?
They want to have a meeting with me, right?
It will be me...
McCluskey and Sollozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be held.
We insist it's a public place...
a bar, a restaurant.
Someplace where there's people, so I feel safe.
They're gonna search me
when I first meet them, right?
So I can't have a weapon on me then.
But if Clemenza can figure a way...
to have a weapon planted there for me...
then I'll kill them both.
What are you gonna do? Nice college boy, huh?
Didn't want to get mixed up
in the family business.
Now you want to gun down a police captain?
Why? 'Cause he slapped you in the face a little bit?
Do you think this is the army,
where you shoot them a mile away?
You gotta get up close, like this and...
You blow their brains all over your
nice lvy League suit. Come here.
You're taking this very personal.
Tom, this is business, and this man
is taking it very, very personal.
Where does it say you can't kill a cop?
- Come on, Mikey.
- Tom, wait a minute.
I'm talking about a cop that's mixed up in drugs.
I'm talking about a dishonest cop, a crooked cop...
who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming to him.
That's a terrific story.
We have newspaper people
on the payroll, don't we, Tom?
They might like a story like that.
They might. They just might.
It's not personal, Sonny.
It's strictly business.
It's as cold as they come.
Impossible to trace, so you
don't worry about prints, Mike.
I put a special tape on the trigger and the butt.
Here. Try it.
What's the matter, the trigger too tight?
- My ears.
- I left it noisy.
That way it scares pain-in-the-ass
innocent bystanders away.
All right, you shot them both.
Now what do you do?
Sit down, finish my dinner.
Come on, kid. Don't fool around.
Just let your hand drop to your side
and let the gun slip out.
Everybody will still think you got it.
They're gonna be staring
at your face, Mike...
so walk out of the place real fast,
but you don't run.
Don't look nobody directly in the
eye, but don't look away, either.
They're gonna be scared stiff
of you, believe me...
so don't worry about nothing.
You know, you're gonna turn out all right.
You take a long vacation,
nobody knows where...
and we're gonna catch the hell.
How bad do you think it's gonna be?
Pretty goddamn bad.
Probably all the other families will line up against us.
That's all right. These things
gotta happen every five years or so.
Ten years. Helps to get rid of the bad blood.
Been ten years since the last one.
You gotta stop them
at the beginning...
like they should have
stopped Hitler at Munich.
They should have never let him
get away with that.
They was just asking for big trouble.
You know, Mike, we was all proud of you...
being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing. Not a hint.
Absolutely nothing.
Even Sollozzo's people don't know
where the meeting will be held.
How much time do we have?
Gonna pick you up in front
of Jack Dempsey's joint...
in an hour and a half...
exactly an hour and a half.
We could put a tail on them,
see how it turns out.
Sollozzo'll lose our ass
going around the block.
What about the negotiator?
He's over at my place playing
pinochle with a couple of my men.
He's happy. They're letting him win.
It's too much of a risk for Mike.
Maybe we ought to call it off.
The negotiator keeps playing cards
until Mike's back safe and sound.
Why doesn't he blast who's ever
in the goddamn car?
Too dangerous. They'll be looking for that.
Sollozzo might not even be in the car, Sonny.
I got it.
Yeah.
- Louis Restaurant in the Bronx.
- Is it reliable?
That's my man in McCluskey's precinct.
A police captain's got to be
on call 24 hours a day.
He signed out at that number
between 8:00 and 10:00.
Anybody know this joint?
Yeah, sure. I do. It's perfect for us.
A small family place, good food.
Everyone minds his business. It's perfect.
Pete, they got an old-fashioned toilet...
You know, the box and the chain thing.
We might be able to tape the gun behind it.
All right.
Mike, you go to the restaurant.
You eat, you talk for a while, you relax.
You make them relax.
Then you get up and go take a leak.
No, better still, you ask for permission to go.
And when you come back,
you come out blasting.
And don't take any chances.
Two shots in the head apiece.
Now, listen. I want somebody good...
and I mean very good... to plant that gun.
I don't want him coming out
with just his dick in his hands.
The gun will be there.
All right, listen. You drive him
and you pick him up after the job.
Come on. Let's move.
Thank you, Tom.
Did he tell you to drop the gun right away?
Yeah, a million times.
Don't forget... two shots apiece in the head...
as soon as you come out the door.
Let's go.
How long do you think it'll be
before I can come back?
At least a year, Mike.
Listen, I'll square with Mom you
not seeing her before you leave...
and I'll get a message
to that girlfriend...
when I think the time is right.
Take care.
- See you, Mike.
- Okay, Tom.
I'm glad you came, Mike.
I hope we can straighten everything out.
This is terrible. It's not the way
I wanted things to go at all.
It should have never happened.
I want to straighten everything out tonight.
I don't want my father bothered anymore.
He won't be, Mike.
I swear on my children he won't be.
But you got to keep an open mind when we talk.
I hope you're not a hothead
like your brother Sonny.
You can't talk business with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry about the other night, Mike.
I gotta frisk you, so turn around, huh?
On your knees, facing me.
I guess I'm getting too old for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's clean.
We're going to Jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work, Lou.
How's the Italian food in this restaurant?
Good. Try the veal.
- It's the best in the city.
- I'll have it.
I'm gonna speak Italian to Mike.
Go ahead.
What I want...
what's most important to me...
is that I have a guarantee:
No more attempts on my father's life.
What guarantees could I give you?
I am the hunted one.
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me, kid.
I'm not that clever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom. Is that all right?
You gotta go, you gotta go.
I frisked him. He's clean.
Don't take too long.
I've frisked a thousand young punks.
Hey, come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Joe, you take over.
Hi, Grandpa.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Pa. He doesn't know you yet.
Here you are, big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
I hope you get well, Grandpa...
and I wish I would see you soon.
Love, your grandson, Frank.
Go with your mother.
Go ahead. Take 'em downstairs.
Go on, Carlo. You too.
Go on.
I got chicken cacciatore
for you, sweetheart.
- That's enough bread.
- I love bread.
But how much can you eat?
What's the matter with you, Carlo?
Shut up and set the table.
Since McCluskey's killing...
the police have been cracking down
on most of our operations.
And also the other families'.
Been a lot of bad blood.
They hit us, so we hit them back.
Through our contacts in the newspapers...
we've been able to put out
a lot of material...
about McCluskey being linked
with Sollozzo in the drug rackets.
See, things are starting to loosen up.
Dad, I'm sending Fredo to Las Vegas...
under the protection of don Francesco of L.A.
I want him to rest.
I'm going to learn the casino business.
Yeah.
Where is Michael?
It was Michael who killed Sollozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting
to work to bring him back now.
I want you to find out where that
little pimp Tattaglia is hiding.
I want his ass now... right now.
- Hey, Sonny.
- What?
Things are starting to loosen up a little bit.
If you go after Tattaglia,
all hell's going to break loose.
Let the smoke clear. Pop can negotiate.
No, Pop can't do nothing till
he's better. I'm gonna decide...
All right, but your war's
costing us a lot of money.
Nothing's coming in. We can't do business.
Neither can they. Don't worry about it.
- We can't afford a stalemate.
- Then there ain't no more stalemate.
I'm gonna end it by killing that old bastard.
You're getting a great reputation.
I hope you're enjoying it.
Do what I tell you to do!
Goddamn it, if I had a wartime
consigliere... a Sicilian...
I wouldn't be in this shape!
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
Mom made a little dinner. It's Sunday.
Niggers are having a good time...
with our policy banks up there in Harlem.
Driving them new Cadillacs,
paying 50% on a bet.
I knew that was gonna happen as soon
as they started making big money.
Papa never talked business
at the table in front of the kids.
- Shut up, Connie.
- Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
- You got that?
- Santino, don't interfere.
Sonny, Tom, I'd like to talk
to you, maybe after dinner.
I could be doing more for the family.
We don't discuss business at the table.
Corleone.
Hey, American! Take me to America! G.I.!
Take me to America, G.I. Clark Gable.
I apologize if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country...
and I meant no disrespect to you or your daughter.
I'm an American hiding in Sicily.
My name is Michael Corleone.
There are people who would pay
a lot of money for that information.
But then your daughter
would lose a father...
instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter...
with your permission...
and under the supervision of your family...
with all respect.
Apollonia.
Hey! I'm gonna knock you dizzy.
Save it for the library.
Come on. We gotta go
pick up my sister. Let's go.
What's the matter?
- It was my fault!
- Where is he?
Sonny, please. It was my fault. I hit him.
I started a fight with him. Please, Sonny.
I'm sorry.
I'm just gonna get a doctor
to come and take a look at you.
Sonny, please don't do anything.
What's the matter with you?
What am I gonna do?
Am I gonna make that baby an
orphan before he's born?
All right?
Still betting the Yankees pretty heavy?
Tell him to stop taking action, all right?
You lost enough money last weekend to me.
Carlo, come here.
You touch my sister again, I'll kill you.
Weren't expecting you. You should call.
Yes, well, I have. I've tried writing and calling.
Now, I wanna reach Michael.
Nobody knows where he is. We
know he's all right, but that's all.
- What was that?
- That's an accident.
But nobody was hurt.
Would you give this letter to Michael, please?
Well, if I accepted that...
in a court of law they could prove I have
knowledge of his whereabouts.
Just be patient. He'll get in touch with you.
I let my cab go. Can I come in to call another one?
Come on. I'm sorry. Come on.
Hello?
Is Carlo there?
- Who's this?
- This is a friend of Carlo's.
Would you tell him that
can't make it tonight until later?
Bitch.
- Dinner's on the table.
- I'm not hungry yet.
Your food is on the table.
It's getting cold.
- I'll eat out later.
- You told me to make you dinner.
Hey, vafifiancolo, eh?
I'll vafifianculo you!
This little guinea brat.
That's it. Break it all, you spoiled guinea brat.
Break it all!
That's it. Break it all.
Why don't you bring your whore home for dinner?
Maybe I will. Why not?
- Now clean it up!
- Like hell I will!
Clean it up, you guinea spoiled brat!
Clean it up! Clean it up!
You son of a bitch!
Come on, now! Kill me!
Be a murderer like your father!
- All you Corleones are murderers!
- I hate you!
- Come on!
- I'll kill you!
Kill me! Get up!
Get out of here!
- I hate you!
- Now I'll kill you.
You guinea brat, you.
Get out here!
Connie, what's the matter?
I can't hear you. What is it?
Talk louder. The baby's crying.
Santino, I can't understand... I don't know.
I don't understand.
Yeah, Connie.
Listen, you wait there.
No, you just wait there.
- That son of a bitch.
- Sonny, what's the matter?
- Son of a bitch!
- What's the matter?
Damn it!
Open the goddamn gate. Get off your ass.
- Sonny, come on!
- Get out of here!
Go after him. Go on.
Son of a bitch.
Come on! Come on!
Give me a drop.
My wife is crying upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliore of mine...
I think you should tell your don
what everyone seems to know.
I didn't tell Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake
you just now and tell you.
But you needed a drink first.
Now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway. He's dead.
I want all inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
with the heads of the five families.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
We need him now.
This is Tom Hagen calling for Vito Corleone...
at his request.
Now, you owe your don a service.
He has no doubt that you will repay it.
Now, he will be at your
funeral parlor in one hour.
Be there to greet him.
Well, my friend...
are you ready to do me this service?
Yes.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to use all your powers...
and all your skills.
I don't want his mother to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday...
Wednesday, Friday, Sunday, Saturday.
- Fabrizio.
- Yes, sir?
Are you driving yourself, boss?
- Yes.
- Is your wife coming with you?
Take her to her father's house
till I know things are safe.
Anything you say, boss.
Don Barzini, I want to thank you...
for helping me organize this meeting here today.
And also the other heads of the five families...
from New York and New Jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx.
From Brooklyn...
Philip Tattaglia.
And from Staten Island...
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And all the other associates that came as far...
as from California and Kansas City...
and all the other territories of the country.
Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate and so unnecessary.
Tattaglia lost a son...
and I lost a son.
We're quits, and ifTattaglia agrees...
then I'm willing to let things
go on the way they were before.
We are all grateful to don Corleone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him as a man of his word.
A modest man. He'll always listen to reason.
Yes, don Barzini.
He's too modest.
He had all the judges and politicians in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse an accommodation?
All of you know me here.
When did I ever refuse, except one time?
And why?
Because I believe this drug business...
is gonna destroy us in the years to come.
I mean, it's not like gambling
or liquor or even women...
which is something that
most people want nowadays...
and is forbidden to them by
the pezzonovante of the church.
Even the police departments
that have helped us in the past...
with gambling and other things...
are gonna refuse to help us
when it comes to narcotics.
And I believed that then...
and I believe that now.
Times have changed.
It's not like the old days...
when we could do anything we want.
A refusal is not the act of a friend.
If don Corleone had all the judges
and politicians in New York...
then he must share them
or let others use them.
He must let us draw the water from the well.
Certainly, he can present a bill
for such services.
After all, we are not Communists.
I also don't believe in drugs.
For years, I paid my people extra...
so they wouldn't do that kind of business.
Somebody comes to them and says, I have powders.
If you put up a three,
four-thousand-dollar investment...
we can make 50,000 distributing.
So they can't resist. I want
to control it as a business...
to keep it respectable.
I don't want it near schools.
I don't want it sold to children.
That's an infamia.
In my city, we'll keep the traffic
in the dark people, the colored.
They're animals anyway,
so let them lose their souls.
I hoped that we could come here
and reason together.
As a reasonable man, I'm willing
to do whatever's necessary...
to find a peaceful solution to these problems.
Then we are agreed.
The traffic in drugs
will be permitted but controlled.
Don Corleone will give us
protection in the east...
and there will be the peace.
But I must have strict assurance from Corleone.
As time goes by and his position becomes stronger...
will he attempt any individual vendetta?
Look, we are all reasonable men here.
We don't have to give assurances
as if we were lawyers.
You talk about vengeance.
Is vengeance gonna bring your son back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forego the vengeance of my son.
But I have selfish reasons.
My youngest son...
was forced to leave this country...
because of this Sollozzo business.
All right. And I have to make arrangements...
to bring him back here safely,
cleared of all these false charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
And if some unlucky accident should befall him...
if he should get shot
in the head by a police officer...
or if he should hang himself in his jail cell...
of if he's struck by a bolt of lightening...
then I'm going to blame
some of the people in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But that aside...
let me say that I swear...
on the souls of my grandchildren...
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.
When I meet with the Tattaglia
people, should I insist...
that all these drug middlemen
have clean records?
Mention it. Don't insist.
Barzini is a man who'll know that without being told.
You mean Tattaglia.
Tattaglia's a pimp.
He never could've outfought Santino.
But I didn't know until this day that it was...
Barzini all along.
Come on, Nancy.
Keep together, everyone. Brian?
All right.
How long have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that, I think.
It's good to see you, Kay.
Hi, Miss Adams!
I'm working for my father now.
He's been sick.
Very sick.
But you're not like him.
I thought you weren't going
to become a man like your father.
That's what you told me.
My father's no different
than any other powerful man.
Any man who's responsible
for other people.
Like a senator or a president.
- Do you know how naive you sound?
- Why?
Senators and presidents
don't have men killed.
Who's being naive?
My father's way of doing things is over.
It's finished. Even he knows that.
I mean, in five years the Corleone family...
is going to be completely legitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can tell you
about my business.
Why did you come here?
Why?
What do you want with me after all this time...
without even calling or writing?
I came here because I need you.
- Because I care for you.
- Please stop it.
Because I want you to marry me.
- It's too late.
- Please.
I'll do anything you ask to make up
for what's happened to us.
Because that's important.
Because what's important is that...
we have each other.
That we have a life together.
That we have children... our children.
I need you...
and I love you.
Barzini's people chisel my territory...
and we do nothing about it.
Soon, there won't be one place
in Brooklyn I can hang my hat.
- Just be patient.
- I'm not askin' you for help.
- Just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
We gotta protect ourselves.
Give me a chance to recruit some new men.
No.
I don't wanna give Barzini
an excuse to start fighting.
Mike, you're wrong.
Don Corleone, you once said the day would come...
when Tessio and me could form our own family.
Till today, I would never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
Well, Michael is now head of the family...
and if he gives his permission,
then you have my blessing.
After we make the move to Nevada...
you can break off from the Corleone
family and go on your own.
- After we make the move to Nevada.
- How long will that be?
Six months.
Forgive me, Godfather, but with you gone...
And I hate that goddamn Barzini.
In six months' time, there won't be
nothing left to build on.
- You have faith in my judgment?
- Yes.
- Do I have your loyalty?
- Always, Godfather.
Then be a friend to Michael...
and do as he says.
There are things being negotiated
that are gonna solve...
all your problems
and answer all your questions.
That's all I can tell you now.
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there,
you're gonna be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen's no longer consigliere.
He's gonna be our lawyer in Vegas.
That's no reflection on Tom,
but that's the way I want it.
Besides, if I ever need help...
who's a better consigliere than my father?
That's it.
- Thank you, Papa.
- I'm happy for you, Carlo.
Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere.
Things may get rough with the move we're trying.
I advised Michael.
I never thought you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a bad don...
rest in peace.
Michael has all my confidence, as you do.
But there are reasons why
you must have no part...
of what is going to happen.
Maybe I could help.
You're out.
I can't get over the way your face looks.
It really looks good. This doctor did some job.
Who talked you into it, Kay? Hey, hey, wait.
Leave them out here. We'll deal with them later.
He's tired. He wants to clean up.
Now, let me open the door.
Hello, Mike. Welcome to Las Vegas.
All for you, kid. It was all his idea, right?
- Well, your brother, Freddy...
- It was... Girls?
I'll be right back. You keep them occupied.
That a boy. Anything you want, kid.
Who are the girls?
That's for you to find out.
Get rid of them.
- Hey, Mike...
- I'm here on business.
I leave tomorrow. Now, get rid of them. I'm tired.
Get rid of the band too.
Hey, just take off. Come on. Let's go.
Hey, that's it. Angelo, that's it.
Let's go. Hey, come on!
Scram!
Come on, honey. Let's go.
I don't know, Johnny.
I don't know what the hell's
the matter with him.
It's all right, Freddy.
I don't know. He's tired, he's hot.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He said he had some business.
He said give him a call...
when the party started.
Well, give him a call.
- Johnny, how are you?
- Hello. Nice to see you again.
- We're all proud of you.
- Thanks, Mike.
Sit down, Johnny. I want to talk to you.
- The don's proud of you too.
- I owe it all to him.
Well, he knows how grateful you are.
That's why he'd like to ask a favor of you.
Mike, what can I do?
The Corleone family is thinking
of giving up all its interests...
in the olive oil business, settling out here.
Now, Moe Greene will sell us
his share of the casino and hotel...
so it can be completely owned by the family.
Mike, are you sure about that?
Moe loves the business. He never
said nothin' to me about sellin'.
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
See, Johnny...
we figure that entertainment will be a big factor...
in drawing gamblers to the casino.
We hope you'll sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of
your friends in the movies...
to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure, Mike. I'll do anything for my godfather.
You know that.
Good.
Hey, Mike. Hello, fellas.
Everybody's here. Freddy, Tom.
Good to see you, Mike.
- How are you, Moe?
- You got everything you want?
The chef cooked for you special, the
dancers will kick your tongue out...
and your credit is good.
Draw chips for everybody in the
room so they can play on the house.
My credit good enough to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino. The hotel.
The Corleone family wants to buy you out.
The Corleone family wants to buy me out?
No, I buy you out. You don't buy me out.
Your casino loses money. Maybe we can do better.
You think I'm skimming off the top?
You're unlucky.
You goddamn guineas really make me laugh.
I do you a favor and take Freddy in
when you're having a bad time.
- Then you try to push me out!
- Wait a minute.
You took Freddy in because
the Corleone family...
bankrolled your casino because
the Molinari family...
on the coast guaranteed his safety.
Now, we're talkin' business. Let's talk business.
Let's talk business. First of all, you're all done.
The Corleone family don't have
that kind of muscle anymore.
The Godfather's sick. You're
getting chased out of New York...
by Barzini and the other families.
You think you can come to my hotel and take over?
I talked to Barzini.
I can make a deal with him and still keep my hotel.
Is that why you slapped
my brother around in public?
That was nothin'.
Moe didn't mean nothin' by that.
Sure he flies off the handle once in a while...
but Moe and me, we're good friends, right?
I got a business to run.
I gotta kick asses sometimes
to make it run right.
We had a little argument,
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktail waitresses two at a time!
Players couldn't get a drink.
What's wrong with you?
I leave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son of a bitch.
Do you know who I am? I'm Moe Greene.
I made my bones when you were
going out with cheerleaders.
Wait a minute. I got an idea.
Tom, you're the consigliere.
You can talk to the don.
- You can explain...
- Just a minute.
The don is semi retired. Mike is
in charge of the business now.
If you have anything to say, say it to Michael.
You don't come to Las Vegas
and talk to Moe Greene like that!
You're my older brother, and I love you.
But don't ever take sides with anyone...
against the family again...
ever.
I have to see my father and his people.
Have dinner without me.
This weekend we'll go out. We'll go to the city.
We'll see a show and have dinner. I promise.
Your sister wants to ask you something.
- Let her ask.
- She's afraid to.
Connie and Carlo want you to be
godfather to their little boy.
- We'll see.
- Will you?
Let me think about it. Come on.
So...
Barzini will move against you first.
He'll set up a meeting with
someone that you absolutely trust...
guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting, you'll be assassinated.
I like to drink wine more than I used to.
Anyway, I'm drinking more.
It's good for you, Pop.
I don't know.
Your wife and children, are you happy with them?
Very happy.
That's good.
I hope you don't mind the way I...
I keep going over this Barzini business.
No, not at all.
It's an old habit.
I spent my life tryin' not to be careless.
Women and children can be
careless, but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
You know, he looks more like you every day.
He's smarter than I am.
Three years old, he can read the funny papers.
He reads the funny papers.
I want you to arrange to have a telephone man...
check all the calls that go in and out of here.
- I did it already.
- Could be anyone.
- I took care of that.
- That's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handle it.
I told you I can handle it, I'll handle it.
I knew that Santino was gonna
have to go through all this...
and Fredo...
Well...
Fredo was...
But I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whole life... I don't apologize...
to take care of my family...
and I refused to be a fool...
dancing on a string
held by all those big shots.
I don't apologize. That's my life.
But I thought that...
that when it was your time...
you would be the one to hold the strings.
Senator Corleone.
Governor Corleone. Something.
Another pezzonovante.
Just wasn't enough time. Wasn't enough time.
We'll get there, Pop.
We'll get there.
Listen, whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting...
he's the traitor.
Don't forget that.
Put it over the tree.
- Can I water these?
- Yeah.
That's fine.
Over here. Over here.
Be careful. You're spilling it.
Anthony, come here.
Go ahead. That's right. We'll put it right there.
I'll show you something. Come here.
Now, you stand there.
Give me an orange!
That's a new trick.
You run in there. Run in there.
- Where are you?
- Who?
Ouch!
Mike, can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten
any of our problems out.
- You talked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security...
on my territory.
All right?
- All right.
Do you know how they're gonna come at you?
They're arranging a meeting in Brooklyn.
Tessio's ground...
where I'll be safe.
I always thought it would've been
Clemenza, not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was always smarter.
But I'm gonna wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet with don Barzini...
all the heads of the five families.
Michael, do you believe in God,
the Father Almighty...
- creator of Heaven and Earth?
- I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ,
His only Son, our Lord?
I do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church?
I do.
Michael Francis Rizzi, do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
Michael Rizzi, will you be baptized?
I will.
Michael Rizzi, go in peace.
And may the Lord be with you. Amen.
- Carlo.
- What?
Can't go to Vegas. Something's come up.
Everybody's gonna have to leave without us.
- It's our first vacation together.
- Connie, please.
- What do you wanna do?
- Go back to the house.
Wait for my call. It's important.
I'll only be a couple of days.
Have a nice trip, Mama.
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
I hope Mike can get us a good deal tonight.
I'm sure he will.
Sal, Tom, the boss says he'll come in a separate car.
He says for you two to go on ahead.
He can't do that. It screws up all my arrangements.
- That's what he said.
- I can't go either, Sal.
Tell Mike it was only business.
I always liked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me, Sal.
Can you get me off the hook?
- For old times' sake.
- Can't do it, Sally.
You have to answer for Santino, Carlo.
You got it all wrong.
You fingered Sonny for the Barzini people.
That little farce you played with my sister.
Did you think that could fool a Corleone?
I'm innocent. I swear on the kids.
- Please, don't do this to me.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me, please.
Barzini's dead.
So is Phillip Tattaglia...
Moe Greene...
Strachi...
Cuneo.
Today I settle all family business,
so don't tell me you're innocent.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid.
You think I'd make my sister a widow?
I'm godfather to your son.
Go ahead, drink.
Drink.
No, you're out of the family business.
That's your punishment. You're finished.
I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
I want you to stay there. Understand?
Only don't tell me you're innocent...
because it insults my intelligence.
It makes me very angry.
Now, who approached you?
Tattaglia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting for you
outside to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife, tell her what flight you're on.
- Please, can I...
- Get out of my sight.
Hello, Carlo.
Will you stop crying?
What are you trying to tell me?
- I'm telling you you're wrong.
- Mama, please!
Where is he?
Michael, you lousy bastard!
You killed my husband!
You waited until Papa died
so nobody could stop you...
and then you killed him!
You blamed him for Sonny.
You always did. Everybody did.
But you never thought about me!
You never gave a damn about me!
Now what am I gonna do?
Why do you think he kept Carlo at the mall?
All the time he knew he was gonna kill him.
And you stood godfather to our baby.
You lousy, coldhearted bastard.
Want to know how many men
he had killed with Carlo?
Read the papers! Read the papers!
That's your husband! That's your husband!
Take her upstairs.
- Get her a doctor.
- Oh, God!
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
Is it true?
Don't ask me about my business.
- Is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business.
Enough!
All right.
This one time.
This one time, I'll let you
ask me about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
I guess we both need a drink, huh?
Come on.
Don Corleone.